{"Topic": "Mahatma Gandhi", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "icwise Questions - Gandhiji", "op1": "Henry David Thoreau", "op2": "David Ricardo", "op3": "Leo Tolstoy", "op4": "Bertrand Russell"}, {"Question": "Gandhi\u2019s inspiration for civil disobedience came from the writings of", "op1": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op2": "Motilal Nehru", "op3": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "op4": "Rabindra Nath Tagore", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Mohandas Karamchand Gandhi was called as Mahatma by", "op1": "Knighthood", "op2": "Rai Bahadur", "op3": "Kaiser-e-Hind", "op4": "Hind Kesari", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "During the Non-Cooperation Movement, which award did Gandhiji return?", "op1": "7th August 1942", "op2": "30th April 1942", "op3": "9th August 1942", "op4": "5th July 1942", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "When was Mahatma Gandhi arrested during the \u2018Quit India Movement\u2019 of 1942?", "op1": "End justifies means", "op2": "Means justify end", "op3": "Neither end justifies means nor means justify end", "op4": "End and means both should be justified", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Gandhiji believed that", "op1": "Ahmedabad", "op2": "Bardoli", "op3": "Champaran", "op4": "Kheda", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "At which one of the following places did Mahatma Gandhi first start his Satyagraha in India?", "op1": "Purandar Das", "op2": "Shyamal Bhatt", "op3": "Narsi Mehta", "op4": "Sant Gyaneshwar", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who is the author of Gandhiji\u2019s favourite Bhajan \u2018Vaishnava jana to tene kahiye\u2019?", "op1": "State is required", "op2": "State is not required", "op3": "State is sometimes required and sometimes not required", "op4": "State is neither required nor not required", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In Gandhian Socialism", "op1": "Non-violence Day", "op2": "Vegetarians Day", "op3": "Martyrs' Day", "op4": "Communal Harmony Day", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "October 2, the birthday of Mahatma Gandhi is internationally observed as -", "op1": "Lucknow, 1916", "op2": "Lahore, 1929", "op3": "Calcutta, 1917", "op4": "Belgaum, 1924", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "At which of the following sessions of the Indian National Congress, did Gandhiji preside as the President?", "op1": "First", "op2": "Second", "op3": "Third", "op4": "Both First and Second", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following Round Table Conferences was attended by Mahatma Gandhi?", "op1": "Winston Churchill", "op2": "Lord Mountbatten", "op3": "Albert Einstein", "op4": "Jawaharlal Nehru", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who said about Gandhiji \"Generations to come will scarce believe that such a one as this walked the earth in flesh and blood?", "op1": "Annie Besant", "op2": "Mridula Sarabhai", "op3": "Muthu Lakshmi", "op4": "Sarojini Naidu", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Who led the salt Satyagraha Movement with Gandhi?", "op1": "non-Cooperation Movement, 1920-22", "op2": "Rowlatt Satyagraha, 1919", "op3": "Ahmedabad Strike, 1918", "op4": "Bardoli Satyagraha", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In which of the following movements did Mahatma Gandhi make the first use of hunger Strike as a weapon?", "op1": "Atrocities on Harijans", "op2": "Repression of the Congress", "op3": "Imposition of tax on salt", "op4": "The Communal Award", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Who led the extremists before the arrival of Gandhi on the political scene for India\u2019s freedom struggle?", "op1": "Dadabhai Naoroji", "op2": "Surendranath Banerjee", "op3": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "op4": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of these slogans is associated with Gandhiji?", "op1": "Freedom is my Birthright", "op2": "Inquilab Zindabad", "op3": "Do or die", "op4": "Delhi chalo", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Who of the following is considered the political guru of Mahatma Gandhi?", "op1": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak", "op2": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale", "op3": "Motilal Nehru", "op4": "C Rajagopalachari", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of the following newspapers was NOT published by Mahatma Gandhi?", "op1": "Navjeevan", "op2": "Harijan", "op3": "Vande Mataram", "op4": "Young India", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": ". Which of the following books has NOT been written by Mahatma Gandhi?", "op1": "Hindu View of Life", "op2": "My Experiments with Truth", "op3": "Key to Health", "op4": "Hind Swaraj", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "In which year did Mahatma Gandhi finally return to India from South Africa?", "op1": "1915", "op2": "1909", "op3": "1917", "op4": "1905", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "To how many years of imprisonment was Mahatma Gandhi sentenced for the first time in India?", "op1": "Three", "op2": "Six", "op3": "Two", "op4": "Seven", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following movements was NOT started by Gandhiji?", "op1": "Non-cooperation Movement", "op2": "Civil Disobedience Movement", "op3": "Quit India Movement", "op4": "Swadeshi Movement", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "In relation to which of the following did Gandhiji use the phrase \"Post-dated cheque on a crashing bank\"?", "op1": "Cabinet Mission", "op2": "Simon Commission", "op3": "Cripps Mission", "op4": "Montague-Chelmsford Reforsm"}]}